{
  "q1": [
    {
      "question": "At this event, Hellen Thorning Schmidt took a controversial selfie with David Cameron and Barack Obama, and Obama controversially shook hands with Raul Castro. Thamsanqa Jantjie suffered a schizophrenic episode while providing sign language translation at this event, which included a service in FNB Stadium, where Jacob Zuma was booed. For ten points, name this December 2013 event that memorialized the life of South Africa’s first black president.",
      "answer": [
        "Nelson Mandela’s funeral",
        "equivalents, like Mandela’s memorial service"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "Z. Alexander Looby’s house was bombed for his legal defense of participants in these events. James Lawson was expelled from Vanderbilt University for organizing these events, which led to the creation of SNCC [snick], the Student Nonviolent Coordinating Committee. The most famous of these demonstrations was conducted on February 1, 1960 by the Greensboro Four, and they began in Nashville, targeting drugstores like Walgreen’s and Woolworth’s. For ten points, name this form of peaceful protest that led to the desegregation of lunch counters.",
      "answer": "sit ins"
    },
    {
      "question": "Most of this man’s work was done by assistants like Alex Gardner and Timothy Sullivan, this man was almost killed in the line of fire at Petersburg. One of this man’s works shows Ambrose Burnside lamenting a defeat, whilst another depicts bodies strewn across the Bloody Lane. This man’s works helped inspire one side of the penny coin, and this man’s exhibition “The Dead of Antietam” was praised for depicting the realities of war. For ten points, name this American photographer who took many photos of the Civil War.",
      "answer": "Mathew Brady"
    },
    {
      "question": "Frank Chimero suggested that one of this publication’s regular features could consistently include a reference to LinkedIn. Kathryn Schulz’s longread “The Really Big One” about the impending Cascadia subduction event won a 2016 Pulitzer Prize for this magazine, as did the work of TV critic Emily Nussbaum. David Remnick is the current editor of this Cond´e Nast publication, which featured Saul Steinberg’s “View of the World from Ninth Avenue” cover in 1976. The phrase “On the Internet, nobody knows you’re a dog” captioned a 1993 cartoon in, for ten points, what weekly magazine based in Manhattan?",
      "answer": "The New Yorker"
    },
    {
      "question": "This city lost one battle after the Count d’Arras led a charge of knights crying “Saint George” and a traitor chopped off the hand of its standard-bearer. One leader of this city, whose dominion was southeast of Modena and Lucca, wrote The Triumph of the Cross after Alexander VI excommunicated him for burning ancient texts and paintings in Bonfires of the Vanities. For ten points, name this city ruled by Savonarola, Lorenzo the Magnificent, and Cosimo de Medici.",
      "answer": [
        "Republic of Florence or Firenze",
        "Florentine Republic"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "Since 2000, a staggering 46 of these events have occurred during Liverpool’s Grand National. In 2008, Eight Belles finished second to Big Brown, then suffered this fate due to cannon and sesamoid fractures. Two years earlier, a case of laminitis stemming from a leg injury suffered at Pimlico in Baltimore led to another of these events, though it occurred months after the Preakness Stakes. For ten points, name this athletic tragedy that befell Kentucky Derby winner Barbaro after shattering his right hind leg.",
      "answer": "euthanization or other synonyms for death of a racehorse"
    },
    {
      "question": "One leader of this country was filmed having his ears cut off while warlord Prince Johnson drank a Budweiser. During this country’s first civil war, Joshua Milton Blahyi led an armed division of children known as the “Butt Naked brigade.” That civil war ended with the 1997 election of Charles Taylor. Alongside Guinea and Sierra Leone, this country was at the centre of the West African Ebola outbreak. For ten points, name this African country, originally established as a country for free slaves, whose capital is Monrovia.",
      "answer": "Liberia"
    },
    {
      "question": "Kepler predicted the 1631 occurrence of this event, but it was not visible from Europe. One of these in 1769 was studied from Tahiti during James Cook’s first voyage to Australia. During these astronomical events, which occur in pairs eight years apart, spectroscopy can detect an atmosphere with much less sulfuric acid than commonly believed. For ten points, name these events in which a certain planet crosses between the Earth and Sun.",
      "answer": [
        "transits of Venus",
        "occultation of the Sun by Venus",
        "eclipse of the Sun by Venus",
        "solar eclipse by Venus"
      ]
    }
  ],
  "q2": [
    {
      "tossup": {
        "question": "This work includes a section based on a Lancashire dance later associated with sailors, and may have been commissioned as a way to “show up” the Prince of Wales. The quieter orchestration of its G major portion indicates it was performed later at a “choice supper” in Chelsea, and its first portion in F major included movements titled “Bour´ee” and “Alla Hornpipe”. For ten points, name this set of three suites, commissioned in 1717 by George I for a floating barge concert along the Thames, which were composed by George Handel.",
        "answer": "Water Music"
      },
      "bonus": {
        "question": "For George II, Handel wrote this wind band suite that includes La R´ejouissance and was commissioned to celebrate the Treaty of Aix-La-Chapelle.",
        "answer": "Music for the Royal Fireworks"
      }
    },
    {
      "tossup": {
        "question": "This event was partially caused by one side’s desire to defend Rudolf II’s Letter of Majesty. One man involved in this event was later given the fitting title Baron von Hohenfall, Phillip Fabricius. Three men involved in this event were supposedly saved by divine intervention, though they were more likely saved by the massive dung heap at the base of the building from which they were thrown out of. For ten points, name this incident in which Catholic representatives were thrown out of a window by Protestants, triggering the Thirty Years War.",
        "answer": [
          "Second Defenestration of Prague",
          "Defenestration of Prague 1618"
        ]
      },
      "bonus": {
        "question": "Shortly after the Second Defenestration of Prague, a ruler with what name was declared Elector Palatine and was promptly defeated at the Battle of White Mountain, thus earning him the nickname “the Winter King?”",
        "answer": "Frederick V, the Winter King"
      }
    },
    {
      "tossup": {
        "question": "A cartoon satirizing this event depicts a sick old man surrounded by various medicines captioned “’Twas a hard old week!” In response to this event, the Aldrich-Vreeland Act gave federal banks the authority to issue emergency currency. A $23 million loan was made to allow the New York Stock Exchange to continue functioning during this event by a group of prominent bankers led by J. P. Morgan. For ten points, name this financial crisis in the early 20th century that spurred the creation of the Federal Reserve System.",
        "answer": [
          "Panic of 1907",
          "Knickerbocker Crisis before “Knickerbocker” is read"
        ]
      },
      "bonus": {
        "question": "The aforementioned Nelson Aldrich introduced this Constitutional amendment, which he had earlier decried as communism, in the Senate.",
        "answer": [
          "16th Amendment",
          "descriptions of “the amendment that established the income tax"
        ]
      }
    },
    {
      "tossup": {
        "question": "This leader appointed special officials called dharma mahamatras to propagate morality and relieve suffering. He attemped to convert Antiochus II Theos to his religion, as recounted in an inscription on a pillar. This monarch erected another pillar that features four lions standing on top of a drum, the Lion Capital of Sarnath, one of many inscribed with his rock edicts. For ten points, name this Mauryan emperor of India who, after conquering Kalinga, converted to Buddhism.",
        "answer": [
          "Ashoka Maurya or Ashoka the Great",
          "or Asoka"
        ]
      },
      "bonus": {
        "question": "The aforementioned Antiochus II Theos was descended from Seleuceus I Nicator, one of the this group of generals, who fought a series of succession wars over Persia after the death of Alexander the Great.",
        "answer": "Diadochi"
      }
    },
    {
      "tossup": {
        "question": "Barbara Ortiz Howard and Susan Ades Stone are leaders of an organization that supported this goal. A controversial projection for this goal suggested that a portrait by John Trumbull would be preserved on the obverse. A similar honor has more recently been bestowed on a co-publisher of The Revolution, as well as the Shoshone guide, Sacagawea. The success of this goal was officially announced in April 2016 by Jack Lew, the Treasury Secretary. For ten points, name this campaign that will replace Andrew Jackson with Harriet Tubman on a certain form of American legal tender.",
        "answer": [
          "putting a woman on U.S. paper currency",
          "any specific denomination, including $20",
          "$10 bills"
        ]
      },
      "bonus": {
        "question": "The success of this composer, actor, and librettist’s musical Hamilton led Treasury Secretary Lew to reverse plans for putting a woman on the $10 bill.",
        "answer": "Lin-Manuel Miranda"
      }
    },
    {
      "tossup": {
        "question": "This body of water is spanned by the General Rafael bridge. The Esso oil tanker was lost in this body of water. Nancy Wexler discovered that people living along this body of water had a high incidence of Huntington disease. The Catatumbo lightning phenomenon takes place above this body of water, where a series of stilt houses allegedly reminded Amerigo Vespucci of Venice, inspiring the name for this lake’s home country. For ten points, name this large, oil-rich lake in Venezuela.",
        "answer": "Lake Maracaibo"
      },
      "bonus": {
        "question": "A large portion of Lake Maracaibo is infested with this aquatic plant, which has hurt the local fishing industry and damaged boat motors.",
        "answer": "duckweed"
      }
    },
    {
      "tossup": {
        "question": "John March led an unsuccessful attempt to capture this region’s capital. A guerilla war led by Jean-Louis Le Loutre in this region was quashed at the Battle of Fort Beausejour. Charles Lawrence invited the New England Planters to resettle this region after he deported most of its existing population, many of whom became the Cajuns. For ten points, name this region of New France whose inhabitants were expelled to Louisiana after the French and Indian War.",
        "answer": [
          "Acadia",
          "Acadie"
        ]
      },
      "bonus": {
        "question": "Many Acadians came from this modern Canadian province, including its Cape Breton Island.",
        "answer": "Nova Scotia"
      }
    },
    {
      "tossup": {
        "question": "This leader’s decision to raise the price of meat and butter resulted in the Novocherkassk Massacre. A visit by this man to Roswell Garst’s farm in Iowa convinced him of the utility of corn, which he attempted to introduce to his own nation and he attempted to increase agricultural production with the Virgin Lands campaign, starting in 1953, with a failed attempt to grow grain in Kazakhstan. For ten points, name this Soviet leader whose agricultural policies were not nearly as devastating as those of his predecessor, Joseph Stalin.",
        "answer": "Nikita Khrushchev"
      },
      "bonus": {
        "question": "Kazakhstan’s farming output is dominated by wheat and, to a much lesser extent, this amaranth crop grown for sugar production.",
        "answer": "sugar beet"
      }
    }
  ],
  "q3": [
    {
      "category": "3. BIRDS",
      "prompt": "In the history of the Ford Motor Company, what or who was...",
      "questions": [
        {
          "question": "the car first produced in 1908 that sold over 12 million units?",
          "answer": "Ford Model T"
        },
        {
          "question": "the union that forced a collective bargaining agreement with Ford in 1941?",
          "answer": [
            "United Automobile Workers",
            "UAW",
            "International Union, United Automobile, Aerospace and Agricultural Implement Workers of America"
          ]
        },
        {
          "question": "the manufacturing process which allowed a car to be produced in 93 minutes?",
          "answer": "assembly line"
        },
        {
          "question": "the word that completes “any customer can have any color as long as it is [this color]”",
          "answer": "black"
        },
        {
          "question": "the Detroit suburb which is home to Ford World Headquarters?",
          "answer": "Dearborn, Michigan"
        },
        {
          "question": "the President of Ford who served as Secretary of Defense under John F. Kennedy.",
          "answer": "Robert Strange McNamara"
        },
        {
          "question": "the 1937 confrontation in which labor organizers fought with Ford security guards.",
          "answer": "Battle of the Overpass"
        },
        {
          "question": "the series of murals created by Diego Rivera depicting the Ford company.",
          "answer": "Detroit Industry Murals GERMANY IN WORLD WAR I"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "category": "Identify from World War I...",
      "prompt": "Answer these questions about Identify from World War I......",
      "questions": [
        {
          "question": "the collective name given to Germany and its allies.",
          "answer": [
            "Central Powers",
            "Quadruple Alliance"
          ]
        },
        {
          "question": "the German flying ace who downed 80 aircraft.",
          "answer": "Manfred Albrecht Freiherr von Richthofen The Red Baron"
        },
        {
          "question": "theGermangeneralwhowouldlaterbeelectedPresidentin1925andbecomenamesakeofadisastrous blimp.",
          "answer": "Paul von Hindenburg"
        },
        {
          "question": "the plan named for a German field marshal which called of a quick, offensive war with France.",
          "answer": "Schlieffen Plan"
        },
        {
          "question": "the treaty signed by Germany which took Soviet Russia out of the fight.",
          "answer": "Treaty of Brest-Litovsk"
        },
        {
          "question": "the type of gas first used by Germany at the Battle of Ypres.",
          "answer": [
            "Chlorine gas",
            "Bertholite"
          ]
        },
        {
          "question": "the crushing 1914 victory of Germany over Russia which led to the suicide of Alexander Samsonov.",
          "answer": "Battle of Tannenberg"
        },
        {
          "question": "the German general who was second-in-command at that battle and later served in Parliament.",
          "answer": "Erich Friedrich Wilhelm Ludendorff"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "category": "BIRDS",
      "prompt": "In the history of birds, name the...",
      "questions": [
        {
          "question": "type of bird used as World War I messengers.",
          "answer": [
            "pigeon",
            "homing pigeon",
            "carrier pigeon"
          ]
        },
        {
          "question": "American behaviorist psychologist who trained those birds to guide missiles.",
          "answer": "Burrhus Frederic Skinner"
        },
        {
          "question": "Pacific archipelago where Darwin described his namesake finches.",
          "answer": "Gal´apagos Islands"
        },
        {
          "question": "19th century painter of The Birds of America and namesake of many nature societies.",
          "answer": "John James Audubon"
        },
        {
          "question": "flightless Australian bird that was the namesake of a “war” that sought to control them.",
          "answer": "emu"
        },
        {
          "question": "mosquito-controlling chemical that killed birds, prompting Rachel Carson to write Silent Spring.",
          "answer": "DDT or dichlorodiphenyltrichloroethane"
        },
        {
          "question": "flightless bird that went extinct in the North Atlantic in the mid 1800s.",
          "answer": "Great Auk"
        },
        {
          "question": "four-letter abbreviation that appeared with a golden eagle on top of Roman standards.",
          "answer": "SPQR"
        }
      ]
    }
  ],
  "q4": [
    {
      "parts": [
        "(30 pts) The legendary Arnold von Winkelried sacrificed himself to these weapons at the Battle of Sempach. Against these weapons, the Doppelsoldners and Rodeleros would break the deadlock created by their “push.” These weapons, which were similar to the ancient (20 pts)",
        "sarissa, repeatedly saved Ren´e II against Charles the Bold by using a tight “square” formation. Arquebusiers surrounded users of these weapons in (10 pts)",
        "tercios, and the colorful Landsknechts and Swiss mercenaries heavily utilized them. For ten points, name these long Renaissance spears."
      ],
      "answer": "pikes"
    },
    {
      "parts": [
        "(30 pts) In response to this event, the Ticonderoga and Constellation launched bombers in Operation Pierce Arrow. Historians argue over whether John Herrick had ordered his machine gunners to fire (20 pts)",
        "warning shots during this event, which interrupted intelligence patrolling. One participant in this event admitted there was a response to an imaginary incident on (10 pts)",
        "August 4, but not to a real one on August 2. For ten points, name this 1964 event in which torpedo boats fired on the USS Maddox in an arm of the South China Sea, after which Congress authorized Lyndon Johnson’s troop deployment to Vietnam."
      ],
      "answer": "Gulf of Tonkin incident"
    },
    {
      "parts": [
        "(30 pts) One depiction of this event shows John Bull off laughing on a hill while the main participants negotiate. Charles Lee and Timothy Pickering clamored for (20 pts)",
        "war after this event, leading to the annulment of the Treaty of Alliance. One participant shouted “no, no, not a sixpence!” in reaction to this event, in which (10 pts)",
        "bribes were solicited from Charles Pinckney, John Marshall, and Elbridge Gerry. For ten points, name this event in which 3 French diplomats required substantial payment before an audience with Talleyrand could be arranged."
      ],
      "answer": "XYZ Affair"
    },
    {
      "parts": [
        "(30 pts) This discipline was criticized by George Berkeley for invoking “ghosts of departed quantities.” This discipline initially made use of a quantity denoted by a dot written over a letter called a (20 pts)",
        "fluxion, but that quantity was replaced with a reformulation by Augustin-Louis Cauchy [KO-shee]. One important discovery in this discipline was developed by Johann Bernoulli, but first published by the Marquis de (10 pts)",
        "l’Hˆopital [LO-pee-TAL]. Ideas in this field were presented in Principia Mathematica. For ten points, name this branch of mathematics controversially credited to both Gottfried Leibniz and Isaac Newton."
      ],
      "answer": "calculus"
    },
    {
      "parts": [
        "(30 pts) Freddy Guarin recently transferred to a team in this country. Like Saudi Arabia and France, it crashed out of the 2002 FIFA World Cup without scoring a goal, but hasn’t qualified for a World Cup since. Shortly after his stint as manager of Brazil, Felipe Scolari found work in this country with a team called (20 pts)",
        "Evergrande. In 2012, Chelsea lost Nicholas Anelka and Didier Drogba to a team in this country owned by the Greenland Group, (10 pts)",
        "Shenhua FC. For ten points, name this Asian country attempting to undergo soccer reform at the behest of president Xi [SHEE] Jinping."
      ],
      "answer": "People’s Republic of China"
    },
    {
      "parts": [
        "(30 pts) An early success in this conflict for one side was the capture of Carlisle. The mathematician Colin MacLaurin helped organize one city’s defenses during this war. Early in this conflict, one side was commanded by Lord Murray, who defeated John Cope at the Battle of (20 pts)",
        "Prestonpans. This conflict, which was coterminous with the War of the Austrian Succession, destroyed the clan system. The Duke of Cumberland managed to defeat a (10 pts)",
        "Highland charge at the decisive battle of this conflict, the Battle of Culloden Moor. For ten points, name this conflict that sought to bring the Old Pretender, Bonnie Prince Charlie, to power for the second time."
      ],
      "answer": [
        "Second Jacobite Uprising or Jacobite Uprising of 1745",
        "the ‘45",
        "just Jacobite Uprising after “second,” but"
      ]
    },
    {
      "parts": [
        "(30 pts) This country disputes the sovereignty of the Chagos Archipelago with the United Kingdom. This modern day country was known as Isle-de France before Napol´eon lost control of it at the Battle of (20 pts)",
        "Grand Port. This country’s namesake island and Rodrigues Island are the easternmost Mascarene Islands. Reports of a “white” bird from this modern day country were likely an (10 pts)",
        "extinct species of Ibis found on the neighbouring island of R´eunion [ray-oon-ye-ohn]. For ten points, name this island country in the Indian Ocean whose capital is Port Louis, the former home of the extinct Dodo bird."
      ],
      "answer": "Mauritius"
    },
    {
      "parts": [
        "(30 pts) This man sent the SMS Novara on a scientific expedition that later led to a circumnavigation of the globe; that ship would later transport his body home. In a futile attempt to crush resistance against him, this ruler threatened to immediately execute without trial anyone found in a group bearing arms in the (20 pts)",
        "Black Decree. A series of paintings by Edouard Manet [mah-nay] depict this ruler’s execution by firing squad, which occurred after his defeat and capture at (10 pts)",
        "Queretaro. This puppet ruler of Napol´eon III was installed on the throne after French forces conquered the country he ruled. For ten points, name this emperor of Mexico."
      ],
      "answer": "Maximilian I"
    }
  ]
}